so I will give an introduction just for
a few minutes and uh and then we'll hear
from Jay from Microsoft
who's working with David and Jonathan at
CBC Radio Canada
uh talking about their implementation of
c2ba at CBC and uh and then Nigel and
Charlie will be talking about what BBC's
been doing around implementing uh cgpa
and then Gavin and Pia uh mostly Gavin I
think that maybe Pierre will be joining
in for questions uh we'll be talking
about the content authenticity
initiative and also the Adobe
implementations because they sort of
wear two hats they work for both content
authenticity initiative and Adobe so I'm
sure they will give you more information
on their approach later on but just for
those who haven't heard of c2pa or have
forgotten uh since last meeting I'll
give a few really quick uh words on
introduction because we do have a lot to
cover in the next 45 minutes
so the general idea of these
Technologies at c2ba in particular is
rather than trying to detect deep fake
images and videos uh we figured that is
going to end up as an arms race which is
going to be impossible to win it'll be
like viruses and antivirus software
there is a place in the world for
antivirus software obviously and a lot
of us need it and so there'll probably
be something to detect steep fakes but
we also want to approach things from the
other direction and to be able to prove
what is at least where the sources of uh
of content so we really want to make
sure that content being published by
reputable Publishers can be viewed as
such and people can trust what they see
so the key term behind that is digital
provenance and that's a term that comes
up a lot so we can't really prove that
something is true but we can uh show the
provenance chain the way that um the
workflow by which content was created
and all of the actors and tools that
were used in the creation of content
ideally from the the lens from the glass
to glass so from the original
uh capture device through to the user
viewing it that's the ideal situation so
we really want to have the goal of
making it simple for the creators the
photographers and videographers to be
able to capture information along with
capturing the the actual image or the
actual video
and and on the other end to make it easy
for viewers to be able to see their
prominent information so there are three
organizations that have a strong
relationship that are working on this so
two that are working sort of on the
requirement side a group called content
authenticity initiative which uh Peter
and Gavin represent and so you'll be
hearing from them later and there's
another group called project origin
which uh BBC and CBC are members of and
iptc is soon to join
so we've been working with them on
looking at the same issue but from a
particular news media Viewpoint so
content authenticity initiative is
looking across all Industries project
origin is trying to focus just on
workflows for news and there's some
particular needs around that and so the
two organizations got together and
created a third organization to actually
write the technical standard that
implements those requirements so you can
see the relationship like this so the uh
Cai and project origin contribute the
requirements in use case use cases and
the c2pa Coalition for Content
Providence and authenticity creates the
technical standard that then implements
those requirements
so there's a bunch of uh terminology
that comes around these things so claims
are the groups of assertions that are
made around whatever it is that the
Creator wants to say so the the location
where an image was created the name and
the uh publisher information around the
Creator the people depicted products
depicted the idea is that any iptc uh
photoshated property or as of version
1.2 video message data property can be
asserted in a cgba manifest a group of
assertions and then signed digitally
using a cryptographic certificate
that can then make that manifest tamper
evidence we say there's nothing we can
do to stop people from uh manipulating
the bits and bytes to make something uh
appear to say the wrong thing but what
we can do is put a digital signature on
that so that the tools can detect that
manipulation has happened
so in February of this year version one
of the cgba specification was released
and uh and that laid out the framework
for setting for inserting uh iptc and
schema.org and other assertions into an
image file using the same mechanism
roughly the same mechanism that's uh
used for ivtc photo meds data as a whole
so embedding as a
ISO based media file format fragments uh
we can go into more details on that in
other sessions but we're not going to go
into the detail around actually how it's
embedded in the file but it is embedded
in the files
and uh and then recently uh just last
week uh the version 1.2 of the ctpa
specification came out and that now has
support for uh including PTC video
metadata Hub assertions as well as the
photo metadata ones so we can now
support other
um
emits data this particular to videos so
we can even talk about episodes
structures and uh the durations of files
and various other fields that are
specified in the ibtc video Med State
hub
so uh yes I've got some other slides
that we can use later on but uh with
that hopefully everyone has a quick idea
of what it is that we're talking about
now and so we can move on to our first
speaker in a session J from Microsoft
so gee are you able to start sharing
yes sorry
uh give me one second
can you see the screen
no no not yet uh it's starting now yes
there we go great
all right wonderful
hi everyone my name is Jay Lee and I am
a product manager working at Microsoft
on Azure Media Services
a little bit about me my Asian woman in
her 20s I'm wearing a black puffer and I
have an office background but today I'm
really excited to tell you a little bit
more about what Microsoft is doing in
the content Providence space
there we go so to give you some
backgrounds
right now we are specifically focused on
Providence in Microsoft Azure Azure is a
global cloud provider operating in
140 countries with over 90 compliance
offerings and we service over 68 000
industry partners and work with 95 of
the Fortune 500 companies
so provenance at Microsoft has always
been a company-wide investment
the defending democracy program which is
part of corporate social responsibility
is finding ways in which we can reduce
digital disinformation and protect
election integrity
Microsoft research has also had a
long-term commitment to investigating
deep fake Technologies and prevention
methods of detecting deep things as well
so they've been key in defining the spec
for province and the details behind that
so these efforts culminated in our
involvement in Project origin as well as
the ctpa in which project in which
Microsoft is a steering committee member
but at the same time while we're working
on these Concepts we've also been
listening to our customers and to
understand what they want in terms of
combating disinformation so what we
found is that Province could apply to
multiple verticals
news media that's a given but there are
a lot of other scenarios such as fraud
prevention insurance companies want to
verify that the claims evidence that
they receive from customers is valid or
Enterprise brand protection where
companies want to make sure that the
public content that they release hasn't
been uh altered certain that can
negatively impact their brand image and
another one is content chain of custody
and how to protect that chain so for
example in court cases making sure that
the video recordings that are used as
evidence remain untampered with and
there's a bunch of different areas but
these are ones that I think you may also
agree with are pretty important in our
lives
so with that as most of the customer
feedback that we have was from the video
space this led us to start building a
solution on Azure Media Services
now I understand that most of you may
come from a photo background so here's a
brief overview of what Azure Media
Services does we are a global cloud
service that stores processes and also
streams video and audio content at scale
and how this works is we take in some
form of it video whether that's archival
content for video on demand or a live
stream
we then encode it which means we
compress and process the video file into
a playable format
then we also help customers distribute
it such as streaming on their own
websites or using a Content distribution
Network or CDN to scale Their audience
and we also provide different content
protection methods too such as
encrypting the content or providing
Integrations with digital Rights
Management systems that limit contents
playback on different systems
and how and this isn't all that we do
but it is
a sample of all of our informed features
and how Province fits into this is in
the processing bucket so you'd be able
to sign your content with profitance and
then also take advantage of a lot of
other features that Azure Media Services
provides
and as Brendan mentioned all of this
information on how to do Providence that
is all public on the ctpa website there
is a public specs it's all version 1.2
right now and so there's not really a
secret sauce of provenance
but it is quite a complex process that
requires a lot of infrastructure
investment and continuous long-term
updates and maintenance we started with
1.0 January this year we're already on
1.2 so if you do the math it's a lot of
updates in one year so by using a Cloud
solution you can get Province but all
the benefits of cloud including lower
cost and easier and speedier deployment
and also less worries on maintenance and
keeping up to date with the ctpa spec
so with that what do we currently have
in our system
on the implementation side we are
compliant with the c2pa V 1.0 spec and
we're also uploading dating to the most
recent 1.2 version
we are also hashing the content manifest
uh the Manifest that's where all the
information about a piece of content is
stored so we are basically transforming
that manifest into a different value
that can then be verified later on to
make sure nothing was changed in the
file
we are also integrated with azure
pivault so key vault is a service that
securely encrypts stores and manages all
your keys and secrets like passwords and
they also have Hardware integration as
well so it's actually Safe Keep Out uses
your certificate which shows that you
are a legitimate organization that
you're verified and they sign this
previously hash manifest with all the
important information with this
certificate and this whole process can
then be undone on the end user side
where they can validate
when they actually view the Providence
content
and we are also in what we call a
quote-unquote it's a loose term right
now private preview basically this is a
demo with a small group of customers
where they try using our application
programmer interface or API
so we have the CBC in Radio Canada which
you'll hear from after me but we also
have a company called router
so router is a Content management system
for government organizations and
provenance is of interest to governments
understandably because they don't want
the content that the outputs the public
to be manipulated and you can see a demo
that we have with router in the video on
the ctpa's uh website c2k.org
so
that's what we currently have and what
we're doing now I want to talk about
what we're planning on doing moving
forward
we do have a lot of feature updates that
we're planning to update on so first of
all always keeping up to date with
whichever cdpa spec is newly released
that they're given as our current
Providence system is more a basic
preview version we're also trying to add
in more features that are defined in
this spec so Brandon mentioned like
different uh assertions claims about
like whether that's like iptc related or
like what transforms you've done things
like that
and we also want to make this more
customer facing and so that would
include adding in an easy to use and
also easy to deploy user experience
and finally the hardest part is how we
can educate customers on this and help
them understand and use the prominent
system
I mean from what you saw there is it
could sound simple enough but when you
actually do it there's a lot of
intricacies there so we're working on
creating a nice set of documentation
educational articles and also code
samples to help along the way
now I know this is much more of a high
level overview of what we're planning on
doing and I'm sure there's a lot of
questions on uh how do you do this
specifically what the process is like
all of that
um but I'm happy to share more but if
you are interested in learning more
about this uh and or if you would like
to preview our current system please
fill out this brief interest form it's
AKA dot Ms slash Providence interest and
I will be in touch
so thanks so much that's all from me if
you're interested fill out the form or
you can directly contact me my email is
j-i-a-y-a-l-i at microsoft.com
and I will hand it over to our Canadian
friends
thanks
very much Jay that was really good so uh
David I think you're going to be sure
yes I'm there I can share my screen
great thank you
so let me
know
okay everybody see my screen
thank you so validation
um hello everyone thank you to invite me
uh to this uh to this forum uh I follow
the other session before it's really
interesting uh maybe this presentation
will be a little bit left field because
I will talk to about the picture and
movement uh all of my presentation is
about video
um my name is David Bowie I work for CBC
Radio Canada basically
um CBC Radio Canada is the public
broadcaster in Canada like BBC and UK
um and today I will talk about the the
test we does with the Azure c2pa module
uh just quickly uh I'm a solution
broadcast engineer for uh for CBC I'm a
white man with a curly ale and really
Enthusiast and with the quite the accent
when I speak in English as you see I'm
based in Montreal and but I work for CBC
and Radio Canada are sorry
the the public company have like two
Network head one in Montreal and one in
Toronto one Montrose and French and the
other one is in Toronto but in my role I
work for the boat Network basically we
manage around 27 TV station 88 radio
station across Canada and we have five
especially specialty television channel
and four National radio network uh we
also run two Ott platform more for
advertisement and to News website
um with like uh or like like the BBC
News or something like that
uh we also have presents and all of our
journalism have presents on social media
like Twitter Facebook and YouTube and we
have a lot of project running on Tick
Tock and Instagram and all the the new
feed the the new more younger stuff to
reach younger audience
um for us the c2pa uh where where we
want to focus on that presently as a
first step for our company is uh at the
if if we look at the first see the three
step where we can uh adding information
in slupa is at the news Gathering when
we receive like images or when we took
images with our own camera but we we we
work with AFP wear or router where we we
took some images from there
um at the editing but for us we decide
to focus on the publishing side that
mean where we took the asset is ready
and we sending that to another platform
like Twitter or or on website
uh that's the place we we focus our POC
basically
um we do the test with the Azure Media
Services
um basically uh the the Red Square on my
uh on my drawing is uh the on-prem
facility uh when the asset is produced
that means after the editing one is
ready to start we have a phase where we
encoded that that asset
um with multiple bit rate for Creative
video on demand asset on our website
um basically all of the blue square is
the uh the Azure Media Services part
then
um Jay just explained before and for the
moment is we run with the manual script
like the transformation of the asset we
push the asset manually to the cloud
this workflows the puc is not automated
for the moment
uh basically the Azure Media Services uh
the process do the encryption of the
metadata and manage the certificate for
seal the information and we add
something that is not c2p related we we
use like a streaming endpoint to create
like a VOD link
um Jay mentioned it on the presentation
also the one of the player we can use to
validate if the um the video asset have
correctly include the c2pa Manifest is
the ravner player the other web page
where you can upload or on video link
and try to play it on them I will show
you what this look like
basically
um
uh basically that is uh one video I
uploaded on Azure and is ready to uh to
play it
um you can see there if I start the
video
you can see there the small
um
I is is in that is the implantation
implantation the player for for the
moment if I click on them I can see then
uh my video CBC c2p apuc is signed
um when but not when but the issue buy
that that is a it's me I need to work
more to put the good information at the
good place and isandor said over AMS
Azure Media Services uh with the
Prototype
um basically that is the information
then a user can see to validate the
provenance of the video here we can see
all of the chain the chain is easy
because I just take the asset and code
it and put on a player but if I have
more step than that as example if the
view come from another sources validated
I can see here the the the chain of the
validation
the chain of the provenance sorry if I
took another web page is the same demo
page but I upload another video on them
this is the same video but without
passing over the c2pa process when I
start the video or almost before you can
see here the small I is in Orange and
they will explain to a user oops sorry
they will explain to your user then did
not have digital signature the video is
still play but the the customer at the
end can said hmm maybe the sources is
not good I need to validate
um
that is that the POC we made and we
continue to try to to play with it as
example uh changing the the bit rate
because you know for for creating a
vldod asset and streaming it to over
HTTP uh live streaming uh we want to
have multiple bit rate to add that to
the internet that's the idea but all of
this mechanism looks like work
um after that uh as a solution engineer
I need to try to fit that in my uh in in
our own architecture basically they're
they're the green square this part I
want to automate that and put that
somewhere in our own workflow it's quite
difficult uh sorry for this slide is
look like
but I will explain you fastly you can
see on this slide if you just
step back a little bit you can see two
different workflow one for our news
website the one on the bottom uh where
is all view the asset that means we
create a video file with time duration
we encode it and we encode it after that
and we send that to um to our platform
the other workflow is the odd the
workflow and the blue one on the top
where we provide video for social media
all of this workflow is is management is
based on live feed that is more complex
because uh we we not have like the tool
presently as a customer to and insert
the c2pa on a live feed
what we think and that's why we are
today like this is a something in
evolution uh we we want to maybe replace
the the green square we see before on
our pipeline there where all of our
asset can be uh and just in Azure
instead the the square of Amazon you see
before that's the workflow we have
recently and after that staying that to
our CDN Akamai the the content
distribution Network and people can
consume the video there
the problem with that is a big project
with our boat digital team in French and
English that's why we look more for do
like a subset maybe of a r set as the
beginning but that is not started for
the moment but that could be like a a
midterm solution
the other thing we're thinking is uh to
implement on the live feed if the
technology go well and we can have an
implementation in live we can do that
the the the the pro or or if like
Twitter go and chip in more in the
development and on the Twitter media
Studio they can add the ability to add
c2pa that could be another solution but
that is another concern but basically
it's a
it's more like a challenge for the
moment to implement that to our workflow
and we don't really have the good
solution quick win we not find it
basically
our edl implementation will be at the uh
encoding level on-prem the the amount of
video we we produce uh by day it could
be valuable for us to implement
ourselves not Implement ourselves but
have like a on-prem solution where all
of the asset going out for publishing
will be passing over c2p that means uh
Brandon touch base a little bit about
that but that means we need to manage
our own certificate at this point what
is the validation of our own certificate
over the Internet after that is all of
question we still have on the uh on the
c2pa project
um
our next step basically uh as I said we
need to complete our first step
architecture implement the end
implementation we continue also to
testing the impact on our own player and
workflow to adding this metadata on our
video
uh we want to automate basically this
this uh this workflow for production of
course and we really add the point to
socialize the c2pa and your other team
like digital team management and to to
be involved with people we do the first
presentation to The Newsroom English
Newsroom this week and we we need to
doing the same thing on the French side
and
I don't know when made next week also to
be involved the journalists on this kind
of mentality because a good
implementation they will take part of to
insert the metadata maybe at before the
editing or at the editing level
and the other point is to uh start the
wheel they presently we not put that in
production even the fact then all of the
player is not all of the players
supported the small eye we see before we
want to start to produce video asset
with c2pa even people cannot see the
result at the end because the idea is to
to move to start the movement and also
in the same idea adding this and this
this requirement to our procurement
process to be able then when I buy the
next video encoder I want to have the
option to add the c2ba option to add the
Manifest and Etc
that's why we are in fastly the Brandon
told me you don't you just have 10
minutes I will try to doing that quick I
know it's a lot of information but if
you have questions feel free or you want
to discuss feel free to reach me uh you
have your my email there and I'm still
available in both language
great thank you very much David that was
excellent and uh yeah hopefully uh it's
given everyone an idea that cgba can
actually be implemented in a real
Newsroom although there are still many
questions to be answered so on that note
uh next Charlie are you there and
hopefully Nigel as well
oh yes Nigel I can see you there now so
I need to make you uh so you can share
hear me
so if I can try I'm trying to start my
video I didn't oh I would say excellent
excellent it wouldn't it wouldn't work
one second ago great thank you I just
turned you on
so to speak so uh
okay I'll begin so um I'm sorry I have
to say could you please be fairly uh
faster yeah we've got 15 minutes to do
you end Adobe okay yeah very quickly
then that's great
um so I'm nice to learn sure I work for
BBC r d I'm a white uh the spectacled
middle-aged man
um and I I'll just take you very quickly
through what we're doing in a practical
sense and then my colleague Charlie will
talk about the sort of The Wider issues
of The Newsroom
so if I just share very quickly
um
I'll Point shout slow as well for you
so this this partic this first one okay
does that has that worked yes we can see
it excellent okay I think I lost you
right so um so yeah so as I said this is
BBC we participate in the in the
technical work in c2pa both Charlie and
I
so um our our particular
um Mission here was to sort of as we
developed the specification was first of
all to try and understand a
specification and scrutinize it
technically so it could feed back and
understand what may or may not be be uh
working with it so what we wanted to do
is actually create some um ctpa
compliant content you know from scratch
just using node JavaScript and just
trying to implement these these
authenticated manifests which as you
know are cryptographically authenticated
data structures
so we wanted to do this to add the
specification development and test our
understanding and of course make sure
that it didn't affect the content we can
still play the files so this was our for
the first thing we sort of undertook
um and and it was successful we managed
to uh produce files which colleagues um
Partners within c2pa people like Adobe
trooping microphone Microsoft all
managed to
um play and we managed to play their
content so that was the sort of big the
big sort of first effort at trying to
implement this thing from scratch
and we ended up with a sort of basic
command line tool in JavaScript so I'm
just showing a screenshot here rather
than the whole thing because this is a
very sort of technical engineering
command line tool you know you type make
a manifest it takes some content it goes
through all of the process of adding
assertions of doing the cryptography of
binding in the content to the Manifest
generating a manifest adding it to the
file so what you see really would just
be a lot of a lot of text coming back by
to uh to verify the operations and and
tell me what the data structures are so
I can actually debug it but at the end
of it I end up with a file with some
ctpa content and I make sure I can play
it so that if you like was the step one
has been achieved we're quite happy with
that then we wanted to try and make a
second step which is to try and produce
a more user-friendly demonstrator which
is more Visual and more kind of looks
more like a professional validator in
fact what we really wanted to do was
produce some more um some libraries that
we could build that we can to our ux
experts so they could build on it and do
some testing with um user experience and
we wanted to be able to think about
making a tool to generate content and
explain to our journalists and our
people in and our friends in news how
how this works what it is conceptually
you know show them a range of assertions
these claims that say you know that we
was produced by the BBC or was produced
by some incoming contribution
explore manifests and just be able to
show them around so we um we started off
uh just creating these libraries
um and and so far we can we can exhibit
we can use the libraries to look inside
our content if I just quickly show you
another screen uh stop sharing and then
re-share with my browser so that I can
show you
um
just take you quickly through
the browser so here we have the project
origin demonstrator
um so I've fed in a file and the file
has been pre-processed with the earlier
tool so we actually have sort of locally
generated manifests to go into the file
if I go down people are not familiar
with with mpeg-4 formats ignore all this
these are just the boxes that arrive in
the file and eventually we get to a big
box it's called a jump box that's a
standard don't worry about that so we
have a manifest store and we can explore
what's in this this part of the file so
I've got the rest of the file there's
video in it audio data samples but this
is just the Manifest part that it's
pulled out and allows me to explore it
look into the assertion store so for
instance I can see that there's an
assertion here and these have been the
actions that have been created by me so
I've put in a CPA to a correct a created
action and when it was published when it
was produced and that kind of thing so
that's really what we've been trying to
do is build this library now so we can
have a more visual exploratory view of
manifest that we create and ultimate
they have tools to create and validate
manifests so we can sort of evangelize
and explain what's going on as we go
into news which is a good point to hand
over to Charlie because Charlie his
Newsroom expert so he can tell me he can
talk to you about how we might think
um how we might think about
incorporating this kind of process into
our Newsroom so if I stop sharing
and I think that should be enough for
excellent thank you thanks Angel
um hi I'm Charlie
um I'm a white bearded man with very
messy hair today
um and yeah just very quickly just
wanted to go over some of the options we
we think we have in our in our workflow
um so we've we've sort of decided that
social is where we want to concentrate
uh because social is where we see the
most
the the biggest opportunity for c2pa and
media provenance in general making a
difference
um just because uh when we put things
out on our own website
um we have things like TLS and
certificates to fall back on
um and so for us just similar to David's
um uh explanation as well it it's trying
to work out where we put our
um where we put our c2pa process so we
think it's probably most likely that
we'll start at this end of of our
diagram
um integrating hopefully with the
nonlinear video editors that we use
um the photo editors that we use to
um to embed ctpa manifests into our
workflows
um and typically this is this is where
our workflows start when we're putting a
package out that's specific to social
media
um which is uh generally
um what we try and do
um so when we go to Twitter we'll cut
something specific to Twitter
um but what we'd really like to do is
with all of the the prototyping work
we've done start embedding stuff further
back in our workflow so as we come back
in the workflow into our video Asset
Management systems and image Management
Systems these are things that in the BBC
are built and run by the BBC
um and so we've got the option
opportunity there to customize them and
to start putting c2pa manifests in there
so we can get more detail out into
um uh at an earlier point so maybe we
can get details about
um the journalists working on it things
like that and then eventually
um we are hoping that we'll start seeing
some of our ingesting contribution
sources including c2pa data so we can
get that real provenance chain that
tells us even more about where the
content came from
thank you
that was great Charlie thank you for uh
being very succinct and uh to Nigel as
well so it was very informative but also
very succinct so now uh hopefully we can
go a few minutes into the next session
because uh unfortunately we had one of
our panelists drop out due to catching
kovid but uh we still want to have lots
of time for the AI session because it's
a really interesting topic but we do
have some great speakers from the
content authenticity initiative so uh
Gavin would you like to start off and
then peer will come afterwards and leave
sure
um here I'm gonna share hopefully you
can see that
yes we can
okay so I'm Gavin peacock I'm a white
male with pearly gray hair and uh I am a
principal scientist at Adobe I'm all
working on the content authenticity
initiative and what I wanted to do was
give you a really brief overview of what
we are doing with open source so that
you're aware of uh this effort that
we've made available to the public
and
um so our goal is to encourage the rapid
adoption of c2pa and help people be
informed uh and also develop our own
applications so the tools that we're
showing you uh we have uh used to
develop our own applications at the core
of all of this is a thing we call the
c2pa rest SDK
and what that is is an open source
implementation of a significant part of
the ctpa specification it's not
everything but it's a lot and it is able
to run cross-platform so it runs in
browsers on mobile desktop server
environment and embedded so it enables
all of those different types of
environments to be able to work
and the workflows that we support are
creation and signing of c2pa manifests
embedding those manifests in a various
forms of media
it also supports cloud and sidecar
manifests so you don't have to embed the
content
um and can parse and validate running
through the full Suite of c2pa
validation on the the data that we have
reporting on that and doing another
thing you don't see as much which is
building uh the Trees of this
information so if you have existing
flange you add it to other content and
start building composite information
that can build this whole tree of
information within c2pa and we support
that and you'll see more of that when uh
Pia demonstrates after this we support a
wide range of media formats that is
expanding we started with JPEG and PNG
we're in the process of adding Tiff and
dng formats we also support a wide
variety of vmm bmff based formats
including heic MP4 mov and avif
to some degree
uh the code is built in in Rust
currently and there's a number of
reasons that we use that performance and
uh memory safety and uh portability to
provide range of platforms and that's
proved very good on top of the rust SDK
we have two other open source projects
uh one is the JS SDK and one is the c2pa
tool the JS SDK supports development in
JavaScript for in browser applications
and viewing content it is a fully
client-side so what we've done is we've
taken that Java the the core SDK wrapped
it in webassembly and it runs on the
client which is great because you can uh
you know view video and other things
that way and it comes with a number of
UI examples for how you should build
stuff inside of the browser according to
the cgpa standards
uh we also provide a command line tool
which is able to create claims and
verify them simply by passing in Json so
it does not require software development
to use this you can just take it off the
shelf
for desktop or server environments and
it builds in Linux Mac OS window and
windows
so with that set of tools we're able to
support desktop applications uh
applications in the browser via the JS
SDK Services which have been largely
built on ctpa tool but can also directly
call the SDK and embedded environments
and examples of that are Photoshop which
Pia will show you along with our verify
site which is a website built on the JS
SDK
adobe's stock service is using the c2pa
tool to sign every image coming out of
the stock which is Thousands per day and
we also demonstrated recently a Nikon
cameras and the embedded environment
being able to use the same SDK there as
well as iOS applications that can be
built that way
and these tools as I said are all
available on open source today
opensource.contentauthenticity.org on
GitHub content auth and we have a
Discord Channel I'm allowing you to talk
and communicate with us and now I will
pass it over to Piet who's going to show
you how this all looks
thank you Kevin
let me share my screen
okay great so I'm Pia I'm a white woman
with brown hair bangs and glasses I lead
uh product design for the content
authenticity initiative and I also
co-chaired the c2pa ux test course and
just to confirm everyone can see that I
have Photoshop already opened
great Okay so
thank you uh this is a photo of me and
our product manager Andrew K back when
we were at Adobe Max a couple weeks ago
interestingly this photo is actually an
example of uh the c2pa SDK running on
the Nikon G9 camera
we'll come back to what that actually
looks like in a moment uh but I'm going
to take you through
um just you know how our our
implementation works for anyone using
the latest version of Adobe Photoshop
and is interested in securing their
attribution and history data so our tool
in uh the Adobe ecosystem is called
content credentials and let's see I
gotta understand
okay the way to enable content
credentials for a given document is
um through our panel but we can also
right click any open document to enable
and once you've turned this on we have
visual indication that this is running
so from our panel you can see all the
attribution information that we
currently offer and you can even preview
it
um as it will appear once your content
is exported so you can see that my name
appears as it is entered into my Adobe
profile there's also uh social media and
web3 accounts that can help tie me
closer to my content and offer an
identity reference for anyone viewing my
work and to manage my connected accounts
I simply go to whoops open in the wrong
Place uh this connected accounts
websites
um web3 is great for offering nft
creative attribution we have a couple
supported marketplaces that can
visualize uh content credentials when
added let me go ahead and actually
quickly add my behance profile
come back and refresh this and you can
see my social media links update in my
content credentials uh additionally to
Identity information I can decide to
include my edits and activity which is
basically the actions I take on my open
documents these are high level
categories like you find in the the
latest version of the cqba spec that
give a general indication of what has
happened to an image along the way
you can also see that anything I bring
into this document will appear in the
assets section and again because that
Nikon photo already has attribution in
history data I have a clear indication
of that uh let me go ahead and just
close this for a moment to
be able to embed an adobe stock image I
downloaded and as Gavin just said uh
stock also runs the c2pa SDK
I'm going to quickly remix these
together
so that it looks like this photo is
appearing on this person's screen
and now when I preview my contact
credentials once more you can see that I
have uh both assets
um that have been imported combined and
uh I've performed the size and position
adjustments
so I want to actually export my image
now I'll go to export as and we have a
section for Content credentials
to include my attribution data I can
select to publish to content credentials
cloud or attach to the file directly
content credentials cloud is a service
that we offer it's a public persistence
cloud storage for my attribution data it
helps keep my file size small but it
also provides resiliency if my data is
ever stripped from my file we have a way
to recover it through our verify website
which we'll look at momentarily
um and then of course I can always
select none if I don't want to include
this data uh so in this way I'm always
in control of you know when and how I
want to share my attribution information
so let me go ahead and Export we'll call
this uh remix
okay
and um we do have uh just a few
ways to help manage the overall workflow
so in history and content credentials
preferences uh folks can set default
settings for document and Export
settings so that way they can always
have this enabled for new and saved
documents to continue their edit and
activity history uh
likewise of course we recommend
publishing the content credentials Cloud
to ensure that data resiliency if um
your your data is ever stripped
and now let's go ahead to actually view
what we just created uh on verify
and we select the image we just made so
verify is a way to inspect any contents
content credentials we can see an
overview of the ingredients that make up
that image and we can even perform
visual inspections of different versions
to see what has changed over time
and if I dig in a little bit more to our
ingredients here's that Nikon photo you
can see it was signed by Nikon
um uh captured back in October during
Adobe Max there's also additional exit
information like camera and shot details
uh likewise if I look at the Adobe stock
image we can even see there's a link
back to where this image lives on stock
so my audience can decide to license
this photo if they're interested
and so this Composites uh provides my
viewers now with a complete record of
verifiable origins of how it came to be
last thing I want to show is how to
recover your lost data so I just took a
screenshot and dropped it in to verify
and now of course you can see that I no
longer have content credentials for my
my image but because I just exported it
to the content credentials Cloud I can
perform a search on the cloud to find
possible matches based based on a visual
similarity search
um and of course here it is again and so
with content credentials cloud my data
is always resilient and accessible
uh so this is actually our capture edits
publish workflow to help establish
Providence Trails for Creative works
from the content authenticity initiative
thank you
that was great thank you very much
Pierre and Gavin for again compressing
so much information into such a short
time so I hope everyone was able to take
that in we will be publishing recordings
of these sessions uh so if anyone wants
to go through and
soak in the information a bit more
slowly where you can press pause then
feel free to go through that but uh
again thank you to both of you and uh to
our friends from BBC and CBC and
Microsoft who also gave great
presentations